DİLEK SİVRİ

Tatlisu Mh. Sanli Cd. No:50 Dream Towers Sitesi B Blok Kat:10 D:41, PK.34774

Umraniye / Istanbul

0530 877 57 63 • <u>dlksyrv@hotmail.com</u>

Birthday: 11.02.1988 / Istanbul



Career Objective:

Highly motivated and goal-oriented young professional committed to pursuing a long term career in Sales and Business Management. I believe my experience, personal traits, skills and competencies like integrity, adaptability to change, agility, curiosity, quick learner, easy to communicate and hardworking will meet the necessities of the positions in sales and business development.

Education:

Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey (2012-2014) Business Administration and Technology Management, GPA: 3.33 / 4.00

Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey (2005-2010) Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering, GPA: 2.35 / 4.00

Bahcesehir Ataturk High School, Istanbul, Turkey (2001-2005)

Science, GPA: 4.94 / 5.00

Job Experience:

Key Account Manager Turkey & Middle East and Greece, Powder Coating Resins Covestro (Feb 2023-present)

- Global responsibility for one of the biggest global key account for powder coatings
- Responsible for powder coating producers in Turkey, Greece and Middle East incl. Israel and Pakistan.
- Develop and execute a sales plan for the area of responsibility, both strategically and tactically.
- Set up, coordinate & execute specific Accounts tactics & plans to realize pre-defined/agreed sales and overall customer relationship objectives, both for the short- and long term.
- Identify long term business opportunities with the account(s) and include these in the account strategy and plan.
- Lead contract and price negotiations with the respective accounts and ensure the conclusion of sales contracts and price levels within the agreed price volume targets.
- Responsible for the route-to-market approach, including the selecting and building up the agent/distributor network where necessary.
- Build sustainable cross layer networks in the defined accounts by both direct engagement and by positioning key stakeholders to the right level in the account to speed up development and brick wall running business.
- Monitor and benchmark competitive products, market requirements and competitive business strategies (competitive profiling) and incorporate benchmarking and competitive profiling in account and sales plans.

Account Representative, Coatings & Adhesives and Elastomers

Covestro (Aug 2016-Feb 2023)

- Responsible for account management activities both commercially and technically in Coatings,
 Adhesives and Elastomers
- Developing long term customer relationship to increase market share of the company
- Leading distributor to improve business potentials and market penetration of the company
- Seeking for new business opportunities for both existing and potential customers

Business Development Specialist,

Henkel Adhesive Technologies (Aug 2015-Aug 2016)

- Responsible for Business Development for the Assembly Adhesive Business in Turkey; and the coordinator / lead for Key Initiative Exterior Solutions/ Elastic Bonding in IMEA Region.
- Potential mapping and analysis of the region for sales and technical monitoring, and technology penetration to non-existing countries
- Coordinate communication and information about business strategy, technical developments, new product launches to sales team and following up sales projects with sales team

Sales Engineer,

Henkel Adhesive Technologies (Jan 2014-Aug 2016)

- Responsible for both commercial and technical sales in Henkel Adhesive Technologies Automotive Dept. for AutoSupplier- Bus&Truck customers
- Maintaining current relationships with the existing customers including key accounts and developing the customer portfolio by identifying new potentials in the territory
- Managing sales projects on key accounts and promoting the new products in industry channel
- Product definition for a specific application and leading application method of targeted product
- Implementing company strategy to distributors to increase market penetration

Inside Sales Engineer,

Univar Turkey (May 2013-Dec 2013)

- Responsible for both commercial and technical sales in Plastics Chemicals Dept. for specialty additives
- Leading sales through customer visits, phone calling and e-mails
- Preparing sales budget and performing to reach the estimated annual sales target
- Maintaining current relationships with the existing customers and developing the customer portfolio by identifying new potentials
- Cooperating with suppliers for technical support and purchasing process

Sales Support Engineer,

Univar Turkey (July 2012-May 2013)

- Responsible for supporting sales administration, including orders, order trace and custom clearance in Plastics Chemicals Dept. for specialty additives
- Performing to reach the estimated annual sales target
- Developing and keeping high level customer satisfaction
- Identifying new customers with business potential
- Carrying out all procurement processes; stock controlling, price negotiations with suppliers, purchasing materials, etc.

Language Skills: English (Advance)

Certificates/Trainings:

Covestro, Romans, France (Jan, 2020)

Elastomers Training

Covestro, Dormagen, Germany (Nov, 2018)

• The Inner Game of Negotiation

Covestro, Leverkusen, Germany (Nov, 2018)

Advanced Sales Trainig, Furniture Coatings

Covestro, Dubai, United Arab Emirates (Apr 2018)

Technical Training

Covestro, Leverkusen, Germany (Nov 2017)

Power Messaging Training

Covestro, Moscow, Russia (Sep 2017)

• EEMEA Technical Training III

Covestro, Leverkusen, Germany (Sep 2017)

• Situational Sales Negotiation

Covestro, Moscow, Russia (Oct 2016)

• EEMEA Technical Training II

Henkel Adhesive Technologies Professional Campus, Istanbul, Turkey (Mar 2016)

• Professional Account Management

Henkel Adhesive Technologies Professional Campus, Istanbul, Turkey (Apr 2015)

Distribution Essentials

Henkel Adhesive Technologies, Heidelberg, Germany (Mar 2015)

Elastic Bonding

Henkel Adhesive Technologies Professional Campus, Istanbul, Turkey (Mar 2015)

Price Management

Henkel Adhesive Technologies Professional Campus, Istanbul, Turkey (Jan 2015)

Professional Sales II

Henkel Adhesive Technologies Professional Campus, Istanbul, Turkey (Jun 2014)

Professional Sales I

Wall Street Institute, Istanbul, Turkey (Sep 2010-Apr 2011)

• English Course

Awards

Henkel Employee Referral Program (ERP), July 2016

• 2000 TL Gross Bonus Reward for Referred Candidate

Scholarships/Projects:

Cagdas Yasami Destekleme Dernegi/Association for the Support of Contemporary Living "Supportive Scholarship", Sep 2006-Jun 2010

Pricing Strategies, MBA Graduation Project, 2017

Chemistry of Nanoparticles on Polymer Surfaces, Chemical Engineering Graduation Project , Jan - Jun 2010 Production of Hypromellose Phthalate, Chemical Engineering Design Project,

Sep 2009 - May 2010

Hobbies:

Travelling, reading books, cinema, theater

References:

Different references including sector contacts are available upon request